Mayank Jain

+91-9340465621 | <u>imayank2893@gmail.com</u>

CAREER OBJECTIVES

Java & spring framework developer having more than 3 years of experience in back-end technologies with experience in core java, microservices architecture applications. A learning enthusiast, with passion to explore and solve complex business problems by developing innovative technical solutions. Collaborative, team player with zeal to lead and achieve the organizational goals.

EDUCATION

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT KANPUR)

July'12 - July'16

Bachelor of Technology, Mechanical Engineering (GPA: 8.2)

Secured all India Rank of 740 out of approximately 800,000 students in IIT-JEE 2012

SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received Academic Excellence Award for year 2013-14 (given to top 5% of over 4000 students)
- Youngest recipient of 'MCO President award' for outstanding contribution to company's business for order data analysis leading to multi-year sourcing deal of critical machinery equipment
- Authored and delivered four technical papers at Turbo-symposiums held in the USA, Singapore, and Malaysia
- Received Champion Progress Award in Rakuten for multi-level coordination and successful implementation of a complex business flow involving multiple teams across domains

SKILLS

Proficient & Familiars: Core Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, MySQL, Matlab, C, C++, Office VBA, Agile Methodologies, Git, Jenkins, Linux, JUnit, Maven, Redis, Hibernate, Kubernetes, Docker

Certifications & Courses: Master Microservices with Spring Boot and Spring Cloud, Data Structures and Algorithms **Languages:** English, Japanese (business N3 eq.), Hindi

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RAKUTEN

Software Engineer Aug 2022 - Present

CRM Solution

- Worked with a team of 4 people to develop Customer Support Tool which serves as the CRM solution for telecom industry by utilizing Java, Spring Framework, Hibernate, and associated technologies
- Responsible for development of the **CTI service**, facilitating real-time customer call data retrieval and customer insights aggregation, **via WebSocket and Redis**
- Successfully implemented complex business flow to develop Customer Product & Services Interface, involving multi-level coordination across domains, facilitated E2E logic gathering and PRD creation
- Created and implemented RESTful APIs and Microservices to enhance system performance & scalability and integrate with internal and external clients
- Provided comprehensive support to both internal and external customers and actively participated in LLD design and code reviews, with a focus on single responsibility and best practices

MITSUBISHI

Software Engineer

Jan 2021 – July 2022

Hayaku Solution

- Collaborated with a team of 6 people for development of a web application using React, Spring
 Boot and MySQL, responsible for computing and comparing the performance of industrial
 Compressors and Turbines, deployed over 18 dedicated machines for resource-heavy operations
- Worked on adding capability to generate insights and sales proposal for clients based on customer's power requirement, fuel composition and applicable safety standards

Strategic Planning

Oct 2016 – Dec 2020

Analyst

- Analyzed historical order data spanning 25 years to offer insights and recommendations for a sourcing deal resulting in cost savings of 35% (estimated \$5.8M in 3 years)
- Worked along with IT Solutions to identify, design and upgrade VBA based automation tools, saving about \$250,000 per year in Design and Engineering Costs